<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: music | takeo.me]]></title>
  <link href="http://takeo.github.com/blog/categories/music/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://takeo.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-24T16:46:55-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://takeo.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Toby Sterrett]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top Albums of 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://takeo.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/top-albums-of-2012/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-22T22:02:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://takeo.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/top-albums-of-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are some albums that came out in 2012 that I listened to a bunch this year. Mostly metal because metal is the best music, and all links are to <a href="http://www.rdio.com/people/takeo/">rdio</a> because rdio is the best music app.</p>

<h2>1. meshuggah - koloss</h2>

<iframe width="500" height="250" src="https://rd.io/i/QFrWPlbYew" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Most bands try to "grow" and try new things from album to album. That's fine, and sometimes results in some groundbreaking material. Imagine if Radiohead had just kept trying to recreate their success with Creep, or if the Beatles just rehashed their early teeny-bopper stuff instead of eventually writing <em>Sgt. Peppers</em>. The flipside, of course, is Metallica. Meshuggah got things right the first time, and have instead relentlessly refined their already incredible and oft-imitated (but never replicated) sound. Koloss is the latest strike in this long-running hammering process, and it is the sound of masters doing what they do best. It’s some of the tightest, heaviest, and most intense metal ever recorded. After seeing them live supporting this album, there's no way it can't be the top of my year's list.</p>

<h2>2. black breath - sentenced to life</h2>

<iframe width="500" height="250" src="https://rd.io/i/QFrWPlWVcQ" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>One of my favorite metal albums of all time is Entombed's <a href="http://www.rdio.com/artist/Entombed/album/Wolverine_Blues/">Wolverine Blues</a>. When it first came out in 1994, it was radically different than what anyone expected from a "death metal" band. The riffs were huge and badass, it was mostly mid-tempo, and the guitar tone was more like a crushing buzzsaw than the standard death metal fuzz. My band immediately tried to write riffs like theirs, to varying degrees of success. Now, almost 20 years later,
"<a href="http://www.stuffyouwillhate.com/2011/09/is-entombedcore-the-next-tr00-hxc-trend/">entombedcore</a>" is apparently a thing, and lots of bands have finally caught on the what they pulled off so long ago. With <em>Sentenced To Life</em>, Black Breath has basically remade <em>Wolverine Blues</em>, with some hints of hardcore mixed in, and it's everything I ever hoped it would be.</p>

<h2>3. enabler - all hail the void</h2>

<iframe width="500" height="250" src="https://rd.io/i/QFrWPlvKXQ" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Growing up in the hardcore scene, there's always been that telltale “crusty” sound that just feels so right when you hear it, but is incrdibly rare to actually come across. Enabler pulls it off. Every track on this album is super pissed and perfectly executed.</p>

<h2>4. tori amos - night of hunters</h2>

<iframe width="500" height="250" src="https://rd.io/i/QFrWPkwI9Q" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>I've always had a weakness for brooding female vocalists, and not many people can do it like Tori Amos. For me, the secret to her awesomeness has always been the dark, dissonant accompanying music, and this album delivers the goods in spades. With <em>Night of Hunters</em> she is paying tribute to renowned classical composers, and the result is a huge, epic soundscape. What makes this album stand out even more, though, are the duets with her 11 year old daughter. Haunting.</p>

<h2>5. devin townsend project - epicloud</h2>

<iframe width="500" height="250" src="https://rd.io/i/QFrWPlj2rA" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Basically, Devin Townsend is a genius. The dude cycles from <a href="http://rd.io/x/QFrWPk_z1w">super pissed proggy metal</a>, to acoustic ballads, to soaring “pop” metal like this, and it all rules. A prodigiously prolific and underrated musical talent.</p>

<h2>Honorable Mentions</h2>

<h3>7 horns 7 eyes - throes of absolution</h3>

<iframe width="500" height="250" src="https://rd.io/i/QFrWPlQ75Q" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>I didn't even know about this band were until my wife went to see her friend’s band play with these guys headlining. I looked them up on rdio and was pretty much blown away (and jealous I didn’t get to go to the show). When the vocals come in on the first song, you’ll know what I mean.</p>

<h3>chimp spanner - all roads lead here</h3>

<iframe width="500" height="250" src="https://rd.io/i/QFrWPlfgeQ" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>One of the best examples of bedroom metal around. It’s pretty awesome that one person can produce this type of quality metal and make it available to all.</p>

<h2>Other stuff</h2>

<p>While I listened to this stuff a ton, I also listened to and discovered lots of things that didn’t come out in 2012. Thanks to folks at work, I finally found the incredible <a href="http://rd.io/x/QFrWPkGHvw">Drukqs</a> album by Aphex Twin, still listened to a bunch of <a href="http://rd.io/x/QFrWPkxC9Q">Animals As Leaders</a>, and a whole crapton of <a href="http://rd.io/x/QFrWPkDuyQ">Steely Dan</a>.</p>

<p>I love music, it rules.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
